# Pre-Commissioning, Commissioning and Maintenance Electrical Engineer

Eng. Ali Luaibi Mayea Iraq / Maysan – September, 1990 07710943518 – 07818484491 Ali.luaiby1990@gmail.com



#### **OBJECTIVE**

Transformation Of my ability, To obtain a challenging position with a leading organization that would facilitate Experience, and skills to create value for the company, Customer, and myself.

### **SUMMARY**

Electrical Testing & Commissioning Engineer/ Electrical Maintenance Supervisor with over 5 years of experience in different projects (Gas and Oil, Buildings and Power Plant), Experience and practical knowledge with Operation, Testing, Pre-commissioning and Commissioning of Electrical Substations, Low, Medium and High voltage switchgears, Electrical Motors, And different Instrumentation Items, Inspection of completed installations to ensure conformance to equipment specifications and typical installation details.

Highly organized, Successful and motivated, Hardworking and reliable, Good communication skills, Ability to work under pressure and different circumstances.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

\*Uni-Tech Company by POSCO Engineering Co. Supervision, Sulymania City

Jun, 2019 – Jan, 2021

Electrical Commissioning Engineer, At Bazyan 400KV/132KV GIS Project.

#Pre-commissioning, Commissioning, Start up and Maintenance for all SUBSTATIONs.

- Commissioning & Testing of Circuit breakers, Disconnectors and Earth switches (Closing, Opening & Tripping) of 400KV & 132KV Substation by using Timing Analyzing Set Tester.
- Responsible for the Implementation and review of Inspection, Test data and preparation the documentation work's as per Inspection Test Plan, Applicable codes and standards
- Applying the tests of VT's & CT's of GIS system by using Omicron CPC 100 and CT Analyzer Testers.

\*SAMSUNG ENGINEERING Co. by ENI Iraq Co. Supervision, Basra City

Dec, 2017 - May, 2019

at Al-Zubair DGS Project and by Gaz Prom Neft Supervision, Wasit City at Badra CPF Project.,

# Pre-commissioning, Commissioning, Lock Out - Tag Out, Start up and Maintenance for all SUBSTATIONs.

\*Uni-Tech Company by Weatherford Co. by ENI Iraq Co. Supervision, Basra City Jul, 2015 – Nov, 2017 Commissioning & Maintenance Engineer, At Al-Zubair, Hammer and Al-Rafidiya IPF Projects.

- Commissioning, Testing & Maintenance of transformers's site by using Omicron CPC 100 Set.
- Inspection the control and protection items of the transformers (pressure relief, Indicators, Winding RTD's, Buchholz Relays ...etc).
- Test the oil of transformers by using Oil Break down Tester.
- Commissioning, Testing & Maintenance of Low and Medium voltage Circuit Breakers by using Primary Injection and Timing Analyzing Set Testers.

- Testing and Maintenance of Electrical motors, Desalter/Dehydrator transformers and different electrical equipments.
- Navigation and setting of Thytronic Protection Relays.
- Inspection of power and control cables by Continuity, Insulation resistance and Hi-Pot tests.
- Implementing work in accordance to Quality Inspection with the basis of project procedure, QA/QC procedure, MS ( Method of Statement ) and ITP ( Inspection Test Plan).
- Loop Check of the internal control wiring for electrical switchgears.
- Inspection of different electrical items related to switchgears, Transformers, Motors and electrical cables by using the following testers:
- Winding Resistance Set for testing the resistance of VT's, CT's and electrical motors windings.
- Fluke IR Tester for Testing the insulation levels of VT's, CT's, Cables and Power transformers.
- High Potential Set (Leakage Test) for testing Medium and High voltage cables and Bus Bars.
- DC Contact Tester of Inspection circuit breakers and Bus Bars.
- CT's and VT's Ratio Tester.
- Knowledge of installation and Maintenance for different lighting fixtures, Industrial sockets and Fire alarm Systems.
- Verify all required inspection report and test records are systematically generated and Compiled to the approved QC Procedures, as per Schedule.

#### **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS**

Bachelor, Electrical Power Engineering
 Awarded by University of Basra /College of Technical Engineering.

October, 2011 - June, 2015

• I have completed PMP Exam Preparation Course

(16th-24th Dec ), 2016

 Training course from Megger Limited for 5 days in February 2018 on Theory and Operation of Protection testing, Transformer testing and Circuit Breaker testing.

## **COMPUTER SKILLS**

- Microsoft Office.
- Word.
- Excel.
- Outlook
- Internet and E-Mailing .

## **LANGUAGES**

- Arabic Native Language.
- English Very Good Speaking, Reading, And Writing.